Amarjeet Singh

- O Una, Himachal Pradesh, 174303
- +91-9816189660
- amarjeet.singh6114@gmail.com

Enthusiastic big data developer and eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Around 3 years of overall experience and have understanding of spark and various big data tools. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in big data industry.



Skills

- Languages: C, C++, Java, Scala
- Tools: Apache NiFi, Zoomdata
- Other: Apache Kafka, Spark Streaming, Spark-SQL, Elastic-Search, Apache Hive
- Databases: MsSQL, MySQL, MongoDB



Work History

2019-08 - Current

Big Data Developer

Reliance Industries Limited, Mumbai, India, India

- Created model for detecting failure of Access Controllers for Security team.
- Used various real time big data technologies like Kafka.
- Attended development work prioritization meetings.
- Worked on ingestion tools like Apache NiFi, Logstash and also used elastic search for real time dashboards for business.
- Developed spark streaming applications for real different use cases (For real time security dashboards).

2018-08 - 2019-<u>07</u>

Graduate Engineer Trainee

Reliance Industries Limited, Mumbai, India

- Created model for tracking visitor movement using various machinelearning algorithms.
- Worked on data visualization tools like Zoomdata and Tableau.



Education

2014-07 - 2018-05

Bachelor of technology: Computer Science & Engineering

National Institute Of Technology Hamirpur - Hamirpur, Himachal Pradesh

• GPA: 7.68/10

- Completed a Stock market prediction project during final year of program, using various machine learning algorithms to train the model and apply it on testing data.
- Completed a major project to detect the credit card fraudulent transactions.
- Completed machine-learning course by Andrew Ng.



Certifications

2020-07

[Advance Your Skills as an Apache Spark Specialist], [Linkedin Learning] - [30 days]

2020-03

[Advance Your Skills as Python Data Expert], [Linkedin Learning] -[45 days]



Extra-Curricular



- · Volunteered for guiding and caring for underprivileged children (August 2015- April 2018).
- · Member of Bhangra team during 4 years of my college.
- · Member of Go Green Club in which we organized various activities and rallies for saving our environment (Jan 2015 April 2018).